The following content is
provided under a Creative Commons license.
Your support will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue
to offer high quality educational resources for free.
To make a donation or to view additional
materials from hundreds of MIT courses,
visit MIT
OpenCourseWare at ocw .mit .edu.
OK, let me make a start.
On the left, you
see the topic for today.
So we're doing pretty well. This completes my sort
of review of the highlights of linear algebra.
So that was five lectures.
And I'll
follow up on those five points,
because the neat part is
it really ties together the whole subject.
Eigenvalues,
energy,
A transpose A,
determinants, pivots,
they all come together.
Each one gives a test for positive definite
matrices.
So that's where I'm going.
Claire is hoping to come in for
a little bit
of the class to ask if
anybody has
started on the homework.
And got Julia rolling and got a yes from the
autograder. Did anybody? Is anybody like?
No.
You're taking a chance, right?
Julia, in
principle, works. But in practice,
it's always an adventure the first
time.
So we chose
this lab on convolution,
because it
was the first lab last time, last year. And
it doesn't ask for much math at all. Really, you're just creating a
matrix and getting the autograder to say, yes, that's the right matrix.
And we'll see that matrix. We'll see
this idea of convolution at the right time,
which is not that far
off. It's signal processing, and
it's early in.
It's part three of the book.
OK.
So if Claire comes in,
she'll answer questions.
Otherwise,
I guess it would be emailing questions to,
I realize that the deadline
is not on top of you.
And you've got
a
whole weekend to make Julia fly.
All right.
So I'll start on the math then.
We had symmetric matrix.
Eigenvalues of matrices,
and especially symmetric matrices.
And those have real eigenvalues.
And I'll quickly show why.
And orthogonal eigenvectors. And
I'll quickly show why.
But I want to
move to the new idea.
Positive definite matrices.
So these are the best
of the symmetric matrices.
They're symmetric matrices that have
positive eigenvalues.
Remember,
positive definite matrices, they
have positive eigenvalues.
But it's certainly not the easy way
to test. If I give you a matrix like that,
well, that's only 2 by
2. We could actually find the eigenvalues.
But we would
like to have other tests,
easier tests,
which would be equivalent
to positive eigenvalues.
So every one of those
five tests, any one of those five tests is
all you need.
So let me just
start with that example
and ask you to look. And then I'm going to
discuss those five
separate points.
But can you see, well,
my question is, is that matrix S,
it's obviously symmetric,
is it positive definite or not?
OK. So you could compute its eigenvalues since it's 2 by 2. It's
energy. I'll come back to that because that's the most important one.
It's actually fundamental.
Number three would ask
you to factor that. Well, you don't want to
take time
with that. Well, what do you think?
Is it positive definite
or not? I see an
expert in
the front row saying no.
And why is it no?
The answer is no. That's not a positive
definite matrix. Where does it let us down?
It's got all positive
numbers, but that's not what we're asking.
We're asking
positive eigenvalues,
positive determinants.
Positive pivots.
So how does it let us down?
Which is the easy test to see that it fails? Negative
determinant. Determinant. The determinant is 15 minus 16,
so negative.
And
that's what's so how is the
determinant connected to the eigenvalues?
Everybody?
Yep. Product
to eigenvalue. It's the product.
So the two
eigenvalues of S, they're real, of course.
And they multiply
to give the determinant, which is minus 1.
So one of them is negative and one of them
is positive.
This matrix
is an indefinite matrix.
Indefinite.
So how could I make
it positive definite?
OK. We can just
play with an example,
and then we
see these things happening.
Let's see.
OK. What shall
I put in place? The 5,
for example.
I could lower the
4, or I can up the 5,
or up the 3. I can make the diagonal entries. If I add
stuff to the main diagonal, I'm making it more positive.
So that's the sort
of straightforward way.
So what number in there would be
safe?
6. 6.
OK. 6 would be safe.
If I go up from 5 to 6, I've got
to do
So when I say here
leading determinants, what does that mean?
So that word
leading means something.
It means that I take the 1 by
1 determinant. It would have to pass that.
Just the determinant itself would
not do it. Let me give you an example.
No for,
let me take minus 3 and minus 6.
That
would have the same determinant.
But
the determinant would still be 18 minus 16,
2. But
it fails the test on the 1 by 1.
And this passes. This passes the 1 by 1 test and
the 2 by 2 test. So that's what this means here.
Leading determinants are from the
upper left.
You have to check
n things, because you've got n eigenvalues.
And those
are the n tests. Right.
And
have you noticed the connection to pivots?
So let's just
remember that
small item.
What would be the pivots?
Because
we didn't take a long time on elimination.
So what would be the pivots
for that matrix?
3, 4, 4,
6. Well, what's the first pivot?
3. Sitting there.
The 1, 1 entry would be
the first pivot.
So the pivots would be 3.
And what's the second pivot?
Well, maybe to see it clearly, you want me
to take
that elimination
step. Why don't I do it?
Just so you'll see it here.
So elimination would
subtract some multiple of row 1 from row 2.
I would leave row 1 alone.
I would subtract some multiple to get
a 0 there. And what's the multiple? What's
the multiplier
in that one? 4 1. 4 1.
4 1 times row 1 away from row 2 would produce
that 0. But 4 1 times the 4, that would be 16 1.
And we're subtracting it from 18 1. I think
we've got 2 1 left.
So the pivots,
which is this,
in elimination, are the 3 and the
2 thirds. And of course, they're positive.
And actually,
you see the
immediate connection.
This pivot
is the 2 by 2 determinant
divided by the 1 by 1
determinant.
The 2 by 2 determinant,
we figured out 18 minus 16 was 2.
The 1 by 1 determinant is 3.
And
sure enough, that second pivot is 2 thirds.
So this
is not
so by example, I'm illustrating what these
different tests.
And again, each
test is all you need.
If it passes one test, it passes them
all. And we haven't found the eigenvalues.
Let me do the energy.
Can I do energy here?
OK.
I am
saying that this is really the great test.
For me, that's the definition of a positive
definite matrix. And
the word energy comes in because
it's quadratic, the way kinetic energy or
potential energy. So that's
the energy in the vector x for this matrix.
So let me compute it.
x transpose Sx. So let me put in S here.
The original S.
And let me put in any vector x.
So say xy or x1. Do
you like xy? It's easier.
So that's our vector x.
Transpose.
This is our matrix S.
And here's our vector x.
So it's a function
of x and y.
It's a pure quadratic function. Can you do you know what I get when
I multiply that out? I get a very simple, important type of function.
Shall we multiply it out?
Let's see. Shall I multiply that
by that first? So I get 3x plus 4y.
And 4x plus 6y
is what I'm getting from these
two. And now I'm hitting that with the xy.
And you'll see the pattern.
That's always what
math is about. What's the pattern?
So I have x
times 3x. 3x squared.
And I have y times
6y. That's 6y squared.
And I have x times 4y. That's 4xy.
And I have y times 4x. That's four more xy.
So I've got all those terms.
And every number in the matrix
gives me a piece of the energy.
And
you see that the diagonal numbers, 3 and 6,
those give
me the diagonal pieces,
3x squared and 6y squared.
And then the cross,
what I maybe call
them the cross terms,
those give me 4xy
and 4xy. So really, 8xy.
So you could call this
thing 8xy.
So that's my function.
That's my
quadratic. That's my energy.
And I believe that that is
greater than 0.
Let me graph the thing.
Let me graph that energy.
So here's a graph
of my function f of x and y.
Here's x and here's y.
And of course, that's
on the graph, 0, 0.
At x equals 0, y equals 0, the function is clearly 0.
Everybody's got his eye. Let me write that function again here.
3x squared,
6y squared,
8xy.
Actually, you can
see this is
how I think about that function.
So 3x squared
is obviously carrying me upwards.
It'll never go negative.
6y squared will never
go negative.
8xy can go negative, right? If x and
y have opposite signs, that'll go negative.
But
the question is,
do these positive pieces overwhelm
it and make the graph go up like a bowl?
And the answer is yes
for a positive definite matrix. So this is
a graph of a positive definite matrix,
of positive energy,
the energy of a positive definite matrix. So this
is the energy x transpose Sx that I've graphed.
And
there it is.
This is important.
This is important. This is the kind
of function we like, x transpose Sx,
where S is positive definite.
So the function goes up
like that.
This is what
deep learning is about.
This could be a loss function
that you minimize. It
could depend on 100 ,000 variables or more.
And it could come from the error in the difference between training data
and the number you get. The loss would be some expression like that.
But I'm
going to use those words as soon as I can.
What I want to say
is
deep learning,
neural nets,
machine learning,
the big computation is
to minimize an energy,
is to minimize an energy. Now,
of course, I made the minimum easy to find
because I have pure squares.
Well,
that doesn't happen in practice, of course.
In practice, we have linear
terms, x transpose B,
or nonlinear.
Yeah, the loss function doesn't have to be
a thing,
cross entropy, all
kinds of things.
There's a
whole dictionary of possible loss
functions. But this is the model.
This is the model.
And I'll make it the perfect model
by just focusing on that part.
Well,
yeah.
By the way, what
would happen if that
was in there? I shouldn't have x -ed it out
so well, so quickly, since I just put it up
there. Let me put it back up.
I thought better of it.
OK.
This is a kind of
least squares problem
with some data B.
Minimize that.
So what would be the graph of this guy? Can I just
draw the same sort of picture for that function?
Will it be a bowl?
Yes.
If I
have this term, all that does is
move it off center here.
It's equal to 0. Well, I still get 0. Sorry. I still go through that
point. If this is the 0 vector, I'm still getting 0. But this will bring it
below. That would produce a bowl like that.
Actually, it would just be the same bowl.
The bowl
would just be shifted. I
could write that to show how that happens.
So this is now below 0.
That's the
solution we're after that tells us
the weights
in the neural network. I'm just using these
words, but we'll soon have a meaning to them.
I want to find that minimum, in other words. And I want
to find it for much more complicated functions than that.
Of course, if I minimize a quadratic, that means
setting derivatives to 0. I just have linear equations.
Probably, I could write everything down for that
thing. So let's put in some nonlinear stuff,
which wiggles the bowl,
makes it not so easy.
Can I look a month ahead?
How do you find?
So this is a
big part of mathematics,
applied math,
optimization,
minimization of
a
complicated function of 100 ,000 variables.
That's the biggest computation
and that's the reason machine learning
on big problems takes a week on a GPU
or multiple GPUs,
because you
have so many unknowns.
More than 100 ,000
would be quite normal.
In general, let's just have the pleasure of looking ahead for one
minute, and then I'll come back to real life here, linear algebra.
I can't resist thinking.
Allowed,
how do you find the minimum?
By the way,
these functions,
both of them, are convex.
So that is convex.
So I
want to connect convex functions f.
And what does convex mean?
It means, well, that the
graph is like that. Yeah,
I mean, not perfect.
But if it's a quadratic,
then convex
means positive definite.
Or maybe in the
extreme positive
semi -definite. I'll have to mention that.
But convex means it goes up, but it could
have wiggles. It doesn't have to be just
perfect squares and linear terms,
but general things. And for deep learning,
it will include none.
It'll go far beyond quadratics. But, well, it
may not be convex, I guess. That's also true.
Yeah, so
deep learning has got
serious problems,
because those functions,
they may look like this, but then over
here, they could go. You know, non -convex,
they could
dip down a little more, and you're looking
for this point or for this point.
Still,
I'm determined to tell you how to find it,
or a start on how you find it. So you're at
some point.
Right, start there.
Somewhere
on the surface. Some x.
Some vector x is your start, x0.
Starting.
And we're going to just
take a step,
hopefully down.
Down the bowl.
Well, of
course, it would be fantastic to
get there in one step, but that's not going
to happen.
That would be
solving a big linear system very expensive,
and a big nonlinear system.
So really, that's what we're trying
to solve, a big nonlinear system.
And
I should be, like on this picture, because
here we can see where
the minimum is, but it just shifts.
So what would you do if you had a starting
point,
and you wanted to
go look for the minimum?
What's the natural idea?
Compute derivatives.
You've got calculus on
your side. Compute the first derivatives.
First derivatives
with
respect to x. So I would compute
the derivative of f with respect
to x,
and the derivative
of f with respect to y,
and 100 ,000 more.
And that takes a little while.
And
now I've got the derivatives. What do I do?
Go down the same direction. GILBERT STRANGER I go. That tells me
the steepest direction. That tells me, at that point, which way is
fastest way down.
So I would do a gradient descent. I would follow
that gradient. This is called the gradient.
All the first derivatives
is called the gradient of f, the gradient.
Gradient vector. It's a vector, of course,
because f is a function of lots of variables.
I would start down
in that direction.
And how far to go?
That's
like the million dollar question
in deep learning.
Is it going to hit 0?
Nope,
it's not.
And so basically, you
go down until they go.
So you're
traveling here in the x
along the gradient.
And you're not going to hit 0.
You're going
here in some direction.
So you keep going
down this thing until it,
oh my, I'm not Rembrandt here.
Your
path down, think of yourself on a mountain.
You're trying to go downhill.
So you take as fast as you can.
So you take the steepest
route down until,
but you have blinkers on. You just, once you
decide on a direction, you go in that direction.
Of course, yeah. So what will happen?
You'll go down for a while. And then it will
turn up again, right? When you get sort
of maybe close to the bottom or maybe not.
You're not going to hit here. And it's going to miss that
and come up. Maybe I should draw it over here, whatever.
So
this is,
it's called a line search
to decide
how far to go there and then say, OK, stop.
And you can invest
a lot of time or
a little time to decide
on that first stopping point.
And now,
just tell me, what do you do next?
So now you're here.
What now?
Recalculate the gradient.
Find the steepest way
down from that point.
Follow it
until it turns up or approximately.
Then you're at a
new point. So this is gradient descent.
That's gradient descent,
the big algorithm
of deep learning of neural nets,
of machine learning,
of optimization, you could say. Notice
that we didn't compute second derivatives.
If we computed second derivatives, we could
have a fancier formula.
That could account for the
curve here.
But to compute second derivatives when you've
got hundreds of thousands of variables is
not a lot of fun.
So most effectively,
machine learning is
limited to first derivatives,
the gradient.
So OK,
so that's the general idea.
But there are lots
and lots of decisions.
And
why doesn't that,
how well does that work?
Maybe is a good question to ask. Does this
work pretty well?
Or do we have to add more ideas?
Well,
it doesn't always work well.
Let me tell
you what the trouble is.
So I'm way off.
This
is like
March or something.
But anyway,
I'll finish the sentence.
So what's the problem
with this gradient descent idea?
It turns out if you're going down a narrow valley, I
don't know if you can sort of imagine a narrow valley
toward the bottom.
So here's the bottom.
Here's your starting point.
And this is,
so I'm in, you have to
think of this as a bowl.
So yeah, the bowl is,
or the two eigenvalues, you could say, are 1 and a very
small number. The bowl is long and thin. Are you with me?
Imagine a long, thin bowl.
Then what happens for that case?
You take steepest descent.
But you cross the valley.
And very soon, you're climbing again.
So you take very small steps,
just staggering back
and forth across this
and getting
slowly, but too slowly,
toward the bottom.
So
that's why things have got to be improved.
You can't, if you have eigenvalue, a very small eigenvalue and a very
large eigenvalue, those tell you the shape of the bowl, of course.
And many cases will be like that, have a small and a
large eigenvalue. And then you're spending all your time,
you're quickly going up
the other side, down, up, down, up, down.
So that's really,
so this is one major reason why positive definite is so important. Because
positive definite gives pictures like that. But then we have this question
of, are the eigenvalues sort of the same size? Of course,
if the eigenvalues are all equal, what's my bowl like?
Suppose all
the, suppose I have the identity.
So that's x squared plus
y squared is my function.
Then it's a perfectly circular bowl. What will happen if I, can you imagine
a perfectly circular, like any bowl in the kitchen is probably, most
likely, circular?
And suppose I do gradient descent there. I
start at some point on
this perfectly circular bowl.
I start down. And where
do I stop in that case?
Do I hit bottom?
I do.
By symmetry,
I'm going to,
so if I take
x squared plus y squared
as my function,
and I start somewhere,
I figure out the gradient.
Yeah, the answer is I'll
go right through the center. So really,
it's positive eigenvalues,
positive definite matrices give us a bowl.
But if the eigenvalues are
far apart,
that's when we have problems.
OK.
I'm going back to my job,
which
is this,
this.
Because you really,
this is so nice. Yeah.
Right.
Could you, well,
the homework that's maybe
going out this
minute for middle of next week,
it
gives you some exercises with this. Let me
do a couple of things,
a couple of exercises here.
For example,
suppose I
have a positive definite matrix S
and a positive definite
matrix T.
If I add those matrices,
is the result positive definite?
So there's a
perfect math question.
And we hope to answer it.
So S and T,
positive definite.
What about S plus T?
Is that matrix positive
definite?
OK.
How do I answer such a question? I look at my five tests, and I
think, can I use it? Which one will be good? And one that won't
tell me much
is the eigenvalues, because the eigenvalues
of S plus T
are not
immediately clear from the eigenvalues of S
and T separately.
I don't want to use that test. This is
my favorite test, so I'm going to use that.
What
about the energy in, so look at the energy.
So I look at X transpose
S plus T X.
And what's my question
in my mind here?
Is
that a positive number or not for every X?
Question.
Distribute the X. GILBERT STRANGER.
Just separate those into two pieces.
It's there in front of me.
It's this one plus this one.
And both of those
are positive, so the answer is yes.
It is positive definite, yes.
You see how the energy
just was right. I don't want to compute
the pivots or any determinants. That would be
like a nightmare trying to find the determinants
for S plus T.
But this one just
does it immediately.
What else
would be a good example
to start with?
What about S inverse?
Is that positive definite?
So let me
ask S positive definite.
And I want to
ask about its inverse.
Is it a symmetric matrix?
And is
it positive definite?
And the answer,
yes,
yes.
I've got five tests,
20 %
chance of picking the right one.
Determinants, not good.
The first one is great.
The first one is the good
one for this question,
because
the eigenvalues, so the answer is yes. Yes,
this has eigenvalues.
So what are the eigenvalues of S inverse?
1 over lambda.
GILBERT STRANGER. 1 over
lambda. So yes, positive definite.
Positive definite.
OK.
Right.
Yep.
GILBERT STRANGER. What about,
yeah, let me ask just one more question of
this same sort.
Suppose I have a matrix S.
And suppose I multiply it by
another matrix.
Oh, well, OK.
Suppose, yeah.
Yeah.
Do I want to ask you this?
Suppose
I have S. Suppose I asked you about S times
another matrix M.
Would
that be positive definite
or not?
Now, I'm going to tell you the
answer is
that the question wasn't any good,
because that matrix is
probably not symmetric.
And I'm only
dealing with symmetric matrices.
Matrices have
to be symmetric before
I know they
have real eigenvalues.
And I can ask these questions.
So that's not good.
But I could,
oh, let's see.
Oh, well, let me here.
Yeah.
Let me put in an orthogonal guy. Well, still,
that's not symmetric. But if I put the,
it's transpose over
there. Then I made it symmetric.
Oh, dear. I may be getting
myself in trouble here.
So I'm starting with
a positive definite S.
I'm hitting with an orthogonal matrix. And
it's transpose.
And I sort of, my instinct
carried me here, because I know that that's
still symmetric. Right? Everybody sees that.
If I transpose this,
Q transpose will come here. S,
Q will go there. It will
be, check, symmetric.
Now, is that positive definite?
Ah, yes. We can answer that.
Can we? OK.
Is that positive definite?
So remember that this is an orthogonal matrix. So I'm
also, if you wanted me to write it that way, I could.
And what
about positive definiteness of that thing?
The answer, I think,
is yes. Do you agree?
It is positive definite. Give me a reason,
though.
Why is this positive definite?
So that word similar.
So what,
this is a similar matrix to S. Do you
remember what similar means from last time?
It means that some
m and its inverse are here, which they are.
And
so what's the consequence of being similar?
What do I know about a matrix
that's similar to S? It has the same.
Same eigenvalues.
And therefore, we're good.
Or I could go this way.
I could,
I like energy. So let
me try that one.
X transpose Q transpose S, Q, X. That would
be the energy.
And what am I trying to show?
I'm trying
to show it's positive.
So of course,
as soon as I see that,
like,
just
waiting for
me to let Q, X be something called Y maybe.
And then
what will this be? Y. Y transpose.
So this energy would
be the same as Y transpose S, Y.
And what do I know about that?
It's positive.
Because that's an energy in the Y, for the
Y vector.
So one way or another,
we get the answer yes to that question.
OK.
Let
me introduce the
idea of semi -definite.
Semi -definite is the
borderline.
What did we
have? We had 3, 4, 4.
And then when it was 5, you
told me indefinite, a negative eigenvalue.
When it was 6, you told
me two positive
eigenvalues, definite.
What's the borderline?
What's the borderline there?
It's not
going to be an integer, but it's.
What do I mean? What am
I looking for at the borderline?
16.
GILBERT STRANGER. Well,
yeah. So tell me again.
16 over 3. GILBERT STRANGER. 16 over
3. That sounds right.
Why is that the borderline?
Determinant. GILBERT STRANGER.
Because now the determinant is? Zero. GILBERT STRANGER.
Zero. It's singular. It has a zero eigenvalue.
There's a zero eigenvalue.
So that's what semi -definite means.
Lambdas are greater or
equal to 0. Wait a minute.
That has a zero eigenvalue, because it's determinant is
0. How do I know that the other eigenvalue is positive?
Could it be that
the other? So this is
the semi
-definite case, we hope.
But we better
finish that reasoning.
How do I
know that the other eigenvalue is positive?
Trace. GILBERT STRANGER.
The trace.
Because
adding 3 plus 16 over 3, whatever the heck that
might give, it certainly gives a positive number.
And that will be
lambda 1 plus lambda 2.
That's the trace.
But lambda 2 is 0.
We know from this. It's singular.
So we know lambda 2 is 0. So lambda
1 must be 3 plus 5.
5 and 1 third must be lambda.
The lambdas
must be 8 and 1 third,
3 plus 5 and 1 third,
and 0.
So that's a positive
semi -definite.
Well, if you think of the positive definite
matrices as some clump in matrix space,
then the positive semi -definite ones are sort of the edge of that clump.
They're the boundary of the clump, the ones that are not quite inside, but
not outside either.
They're lying right
on the edge of positive definite matrices.
Let me just take a look.
So what about a matrix
of all 1's?
What's the story on that one? Positive
definite? All the numbers are positive.
Or positive semi -definite
or indefinite? What do you think here?
1, 1, all 1's.
Semi -definite. GILBERT STRANGER.
Semi -definite? Sounds like a good guess.
Do you know what the eigenvalues
of this matrix would be?
0, 3, 0, and 0. GILBERT STRANGER. 3, 0, and
0. Why did you say that?
It's too linearly dependent on the columns. GILBERT STRANGER. Because we
only have the rank is? 1, 1. GILBERT STRANGER. Yeah, well, introduce that
key word. The rank is 1.
So there's only one
non -zero eigenvalue.
And then the trace tells
me that that number is 3.
So this is
a positive, positive semi -definite matrix.
So all these tests
change a little
for semi -definite. The
eigenvalue is greater or equal to 0.
The energy is
greater or equal to 0.
The A transpose A, but now
I don't require, oh, I didn't discuss this.
But semi -definite would
allow dependent columns.
By the way, you've got to do this for me. Write
that matrix as A transpose times A, just to see that
it's semi -definite.
So
write that as A transpose A.
Yeah?
If it's a rank 1 matrix,
you know what it must look like.
A transpose A. How many terms am I going to
have
in this?
And now I'm thinking
back to the very beginning of this course.
If I
pulled off the pieces,
in general, this is lambda 1
times the first eigenvector,
times the first eigenvector, transpose. Wouldn't A just be a vector
of 3 1s? GILBERT STRANGER. Yeah, it would just be a vector of 3 1s.
Yeah.
GILBERT STRANGER. The
usual picture.
This is the same as the Q lambda Q transpose. This
is the big, big fact for any symmetric matrix.
And this is symmetric.
But its rank is only 1.
So that
lambda 2 is 0 for that matrix.
Lambda 3 is 0 for that matrix.
Eigenvector
is the vector 1, 1, 1.
So this
would be 3 times 1, 1, 1. Oh, I have to do.
Yeah.
So
I was
going to do 3 times 1, 1, 1 times 1, 1, 1.
But that gives me 3, 3, 3.
That's not right.
Normalize them. GILBERT STRANGER. I have to normalize them. That's right.
Yeah. So that's a vector whose length is square root of 3. So I have to
divide by that.
And I have to divide by it.
And then the 3 cancels the square root of 3s. And I'm just left
with the 1, 1, 1, 1, 1, 1, 1. Yeah. GILBERT STRANGER. So there is
a matrix, one of our building block
type matrices, because it only has one
non -zero eigenvalue. Its rank
is 1. So it could not be positive definite.
It's singular.
But it is
positive semi -definite, because
that eigenvalue is positive.
OK.
So you've
got the idea of positive definite matrices.
Again,
any one of those five tests is
enough to show that it's positive definite.
And so what's my goal next week?
Value decomposition and all that that leads
us to.
We're there now,
ready for
the SVD.
OK. Have a good weekend. And see you. Oh, I see you on
Tuesday, I guess, right? Not Monday, but Tuesday next week.